Register to the Papers of Kurt Weill and Lotte Lenya
Yale University Music Library
- Music by Weill, 1913-1983; Series I; 23.3' (41 boxes)
  - Operas, Operettas, Musicals, and Ballets, I.A
    - [Love life], [1947].; 1 score ([738] p. in various pagings); 38 cm. (Box 17; 103; 17, Folder 283-289; 290; 291-309)
      Holograph in ink with pencil and red and blue pencil additions, in part manuscript in Irving Schlein's hand [David Drew], and duplicate copies.
      Lyrics by Alan Jay Lerner, not included.
      Contents (Numbers assigned by Drew appear in brackets]: Part I: Opening (17 sheets, original and copy). New opening (3 sheets). [3a] Who is Samuel Cooper? (45 sheets). [4] Here I'll stay (19, a-h sheets). [5] Progress (32 sheets). Progress (soft shoe) (12 sheets). [6] I remember it well (9 sheets). I remember it well: reprise (10 sheets). [7b] Green-up time (24 [i.e. 25] sheets). [7c] Green-up Polka (pp. 25-73). [8] Economics (17 sheets, original and 4 copies, 3 positive and 1 negative). [9] Susan's dream [...and "After Susan's dream"] (17, [1] sheets). [10] Mother's getting nervous (19 sheets). [10a] Mother's getting nervous [Mother's getting nervous (Dance and pg. 1A-B-C-)] (3, 17 sheets). [12] My kind of night (18 sheets). [14] Blues (45 sheets, sheets 37-41 laid in). [18] I'm your man (37 sheets). [19] You understand me so (8 sheets). [19a] 1st Act ending (10 sheets). [1st Act ending] (sheets 9A-D). - Part II: Ouverture [...(played as Entr'acte)] (25 sheets). [20] "Orch. version of a capella madrigal 'Billy 0'" [note by David Drew on top of p. A] [Madrigal] (sheets A-E). [22] Is it him or is it me? (21 sheets). [24] Ballet Music [Divorce ballet] (54 sheets). [23x] Locker room (51 sheets). [25] This is the life (36 sheets). [20] Introduction minstrel show (sheets a-e). [20] Minstrel show (55 sheets). [20d] Mr. Right (23 sheets). [Finale "Love life"] (sheets 8A-i). Finale (28 sheets). Unidentified single pages (pp. 20, 35).
    - [Love life] [microform]. - [New Haven, Connecticut]: Yale University Photographic Services, 1983., 1 microfilm reel: negative; 35 mm. (Box 108)
      Copy of holograph full score.
    - [Love life], 20 parts; 32 cm. R. 8, Fr. 4-863. R. 9, Fr. 1-642. (Box 18; 19; 20, Folder 310-317; 318-324; 325-327)
      For clarinet I/alto saxophone I, clarinet II/alto saxophone II/bass clarinet, clarinet III/flute, tenor saxophone, clarinet IV/tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, bassoon, trumpet I-II, trumpet III, trombone, violin A-C, violoncello, double bass, percussion, guitar/banjo, and piano-conductor [orchestration for Love life] (16 sheets) laid in].
      Published parts entitled National melodies, arranged by Chas. J. Roberts (New York: Carl Fischer) laid in with some of the manuscript parts.
    - [Love life. Blues; arr.], Blues. (Box 20, Folder 328)
      2 sheets of music; 34 cm. R. 9, Fr. 643-644.
    - [Love life. Divorce ballet. Short score], 1 short score (10 sheets); 34 cm. R. 9, Fr. 645-654. (Box 20, Folder 329)
      Photocopies of miscellaneous sheets laid in ([26] sheets).
    - [Love life. Green-up time], 19 parts; 31 cm. R. 9, Fr. 655-847. (Box 20, Folder 330)
      For clarinet I-IV, bassoon, trumpet I-III, trombone, percussion, guitar, piano, violin A(3)-B(2)-C, violoncello, and double bass.
    - [Love life. Green-up time. Vocal score] Green-up time / music by Kurt Weill; words by Alan Jay Lerner. - New York: Chappell, c1948., 1 vocal score (5 p.) 31 cm. (Box 20, Folder 331)
      Pl. no.: 1576-4.
      "Boston 1966" - old envelope.
    - [Love life. Green-up time polka; arr.] "Green-up" Polka., 8 sheets of music; 35 cm. R. 9, Fr. 848-855. (Box 20, Folder 332)
      Arranged for piano?.
      Two copies laid in.
    - [Love life. Here I'll stay], 38 parts; 31 cm. R. 9, Fr. 856-964. (Box 20, Folder 333)
      For clarinet I-IV, clarinet III-IV/tenor saxophone, bassoon, bassoon/tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, trumpet I-III, trombone, percussion, guitar, violin A-C, violoncello, and double bass.
    - [Love life. Here I'll stay; arr.] Here I'll stay: fox trot / music by Kurt Weill dance orch. arr. by Jack Mason; words by Alan Jay Lerner. - New York: Chappell, c1948., 14 parts; 27 cm. (Box 20, Folder 334)
      For alto saxophone (2), tenor saxophone (2), baritone saxophone, trumpet (2), trombone (3), violin, double bass, guitar, and piano.
      [Love life. Here I'll stay; arr. Short score].
      1 short score ([6] p.); 32 cm. R. 10, Fr. 1-6.
      Manuscript in black and blue ink.
      Photocopy (incomplete) laid in.
    - [Love life. I'm your man. Vocal score] I'm your man: Finale Ist Act., 1 vocal score (20 p.); 32 cm. R. 10, Fr. 7-28. (Box 20, Folder 336)
      Manuscript in ink and purple pencil.
    - [Love life. Is it him or is it me. Short score] Is it him or is it me?, 1 short score ([4] p.); 32 cm. R. 10, Fr. 29-32. (Box 20, Folder 336)
    - [Love life. Is it him or is it me. Text] Is it him or is it me: from "Love life" / lyrics by Alan J. Lerner., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 20, Folder 336)
    - [Love life. Libretto] Love life: (1949)., [90] sheets in various pagings; 28 cm. R. 10, Fr. 33-124. (Box 20, Folder 337)
    - [Love life. Libretto] Love life., 63, 37 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 20, Folder 338)
    - [Love life. Libretto] Love life / music by Kurt Weill; book and lyrics by Alan Jay Lerner., [104] sheets in various pagings; 28 cm. (Box 21, Folder 339)
      Incomplete, missing Part I/Act 5, and Part II/Act 2.
      Contains some duplicate sheets.
    - [Love life. Libretto. German], 68 sheets; 30 cm. (Box 21, Folder 340)
      "... Baden-Baden..." - old cover.
    - [Love life. Love song] Love song: 11A., 14 parts; 28-36 cm. (Box 21, Folder 341)
      Manuscript (photocopies).
      For piano, reeds I-IV, trumpet I-III, trombone, violin A-C, double bass, and conductor.
    - [Love life. Love song (Reprise)] Reprise: Love song., 15 parts; 32-36 cm. R. 10, Fr. 128-153. (Box 21, Folder 341)
      Manuscript in copyist's hand in ink (in part, photocopies).
      For piano, reed I-IV, trombone, percussion, guitar, violin A-C, and double bass.
    - [Love life. Love song (Sketches)], [3] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 10, Fr. 125-127. (Box 21, Folder 341)
      "E major" - p. [1].
      See also: Lady in the dark (Sketches).
    - [Love life. Love song. Text] Ocean song: from "Love life" / text by Alan Lerner., [1] sheet 28 cm. (Box 21, Folder 341)
    - [Love life. Mother's getting nervous. Vocal score (Sketches)] Mother's getting nervous., 3 scores (7, 6, 6 p.); 33 cm. R. 10, Fr. 154-165. (Box 21, Folder 342)
      Manuscript in ink (in part, photocopies).
    - [Love life. Mr. Right. Vocal score] Mr. Right., 1 vocal score (8 p.); 32-36 cm. (Box 21, Folder 342)
      Six copies.
    - [Love life. My kind of night. Vocal score] My kind of night., 1 vocal score (10 p.); 32 cm. (Box 21, Folder 342)
      Manuscript (photocopy) with pencil additions.
      Two copies, one incomplete.
    - Love life. Ocean song
      See: Love life. Love song.
    - [Love life (Sketches)], [357] p. of music; 32-35 cm. (Box 21, Folder 343-344)
      Contents [Numbers and titles assigned by Drew appear in brackets]: [2] Magician's music (cut) ([3] p.). [2b. Magician's exit] ([2] p.). [3a. Who is Samuel Cooper?] ([16] p.). [4. Here I'll stay] ([12] p.). [5. Progress] ([19] p.). [6. I remember it well] ([7] p.). [7b] Verse Green-up time ([17] p.). [8] Economics ([10] p.). [9] Susan's dream Sept. 20 ([6] p.). [10] Mother's getting nervous (4 p.). [11z] Suffragette meeting ([46] p.). [12] My kind of night ([7] p.). [13] Csardas ([4] p.). [14. Women's Club Blues] (20 p.). [15x. Love song] ([4] p.). [16y. Drinking song] [4] p.). [17] Rhumba [There's nothing left for Daddy (but the Rhumba) and Havana Tango] ([18] p.). [18. I'm your man] ([4] p.). [19] You understand me so ([7] p.). 20. Madrigal [16] p.). [21z. Where do I belong?] ([6] p.). [22. Is it him or is it me?] ([8] p.). [23x. Looker Room] [16] p.). [24] Ballet-Music ("second theme from, 7 Todsünden, later discarded from Ballet" [note by David Drew] ([11] p.). [25] This is the life ([14] p.). [26. Minstrel show] ([42] p.). [26d] Mr. Right ([3] p.). [26. Finale] ([4] p.). [27z "Baby" Sept. 17 [There's gonna be a New Year for baby] ([2] p.). [28z] Mr. Right and Mrs. Dream (2 p.). [Various themes and ideas] ([13] p.). Unused sketch "Is it him or..." (Verse What more do I want...] ([6] p.). [Why is my head spinning around...] ([4] p.).
    - [Love life (Sketches)] Love life: sketches, pencil [microform]. - [New Haven, Connecticut]: Yale University Photographic Services, 1983., 1 microfilm reel: negative; 35 mm. (Box 108)
      Microfilm of holograph sketches for "Suffragette meeting" and "Finale" are on a separate reel.
    - [Love life (Sketches)] Suffragette scene: Sketches, pencil [microform]. - [New Haven, Connecticut]: Yale University Photographic Services, 1983., 1 microfilm reel: negative; 35 mm. (Box 109)
      Microfilm of holograph sketches for the "Suffragette meeting" and "Finale."
    - [Love life. Susan's dream], 19 parts; 31 cm. R. 10, Fr. 166-205. (Box 21, Folder 345)
      For piano, clarinet I-IV, bassoon, trumpet I-III, percussion, guitar, violin A-C, violoncello, and double bass.
    - [Love life. This is the life. Vocal score] This is the life / music by Kurt Weill; words by Alan Jay Lerner. - New York: Chappell, c1948., 1 vocal score (15 p.); 31 cm. (Box 21, Folder 345)
      Pl. no.: 1595.
    - [Love life. Vocal score], 1 vocal score ([300] p. in various pagings); 32 cm. (Box 22; 23, Folder 346-351; 352-355)
      Holograph in ink, in part copies with pencil and ink additions in Kurt Weill's hand as well as in other hands.
      Contents [Numbers assigned by Drew appear in brackets]: Part I: After Magician's exit (2 sheets, original and 2 copies). [3a] Who is Samuel Cooper? (23 sheets, original and 6 incomplete copies). [4] Here I'll stay (1st verse) [stage version] (2 sheets). [4] Here I'll stay ("A dish for the Gods") ["C major... with published verse" (McGlinn]] (4 sheets, c1947). [5] Progress (19 sheets, original and 4 copies). I remember it well (5 sheets, original and 2 copies, 1 incomplete). [7b] Green-up time ("with dance" [McGlinn]] (12 sheets, original and 2 copies). Green-up time (Double Quartette) [vocal arrangement] (3 sheets, original and copy). Green-up time [early version - "A dish for the gods" [McGlinn]] (5 sheets, original and copy, c1947). [81 Economics (11 sheets, original and 2 copies, 1 incomplete). [9] Susan's dream (14 sheets). [10] Mother's getting nervous (9 sheets, original and 2 copies). [12] My kind of night (9 sheets). [14] Blues [Woman's Club Blues] (15 sheets, original and 2 copies). [19] You understand me so (4 sheets). [18] I'm your man (18 sheets, original and copy). - Part II: [20] Madrigal (a capella [sic] chorus) (22 sheets, c1948). [22] Is it him or is it me? (orchestra sketch) (6 sheets, original and 3 copies). [22] Is it him or is it me? (5 sheets, c1948). [23x] Looker room (21 sheets, 15 copies, incomplete). [25] This is the life (14 sheets, original and copy, c1947). [20] Minstrel show (27 sheets, original and 3 copies). [20d] Mr. Right (8 sheets, original and copy). [20] Finale (13 sheets, original and 17 copies, some incomplete). [11] Verse for "Mother's getting nervous" (2 p.). [25] Intro. "This is the life" ([1] sheet). [13y] Tempo di Csardas (3 sheets). [13y] Csardas (5 sheets, original and copy). [13y] Love (6 sheets). [16y] Drinking Song (4 sheets, original and copy). [17] There's nothing left for Daddy (but the Rhumba) (9 sheets). Loose sheets ([35] p., copies).
      Notes on the folders as well as the order of songs within the show are by John McGlinn.
    - [Love life. Vocal score] [microform]. - [New Haven, Connecticut]: Yale University Photographic Services, 1983., 1 microfilm reel: negative; 35 mm. (Box 109)
      Microfilm of holograph vocal score, notes on folders also microfilmed.
    - [Mahagonny], 1927 May.; 1 score (78 p.); 34 cm. (Box 24, Folder 356)
      Holograph in ink, with pencil additions.
      Words by Brecht.
      At end: Mai 1927. Berlin - Charlottenburg.
    - [Mahagonny] Kleines Mahagonny [microform] / Kurt Weill. - [New Haven, Connecticut] Yale University Photographic Services, 1982., 1 microfilm reel: negative; 35 mm. (Box 109)
      Microfilm of holograph score.
      Contents: Mahagonny. Vocal score. - Mahagonny (Sketches).
    - Mahagonny, See also.: Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny.
    - [Mahagonny (Sketches)], [4] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 24, Folder 357)
      "Mahagonny - Benares Song" - in red pencil on top of p. [1]. Acid-free folder with notes laid in.
      See also: Mahagonny [microform]; and unidentified sketches [copies of originals belonging to O. W. Neighbour, given to Yale University Music Library, on p. numbered "12"] in C. Theater and Radio scores. Gustav III (Sketches).
    - Mahagonny Songspiel
    - [Mahagonny. Vocal score] Mahagonny: ein Songspiel / Musik von Kurt Weill; Text von Bert Brecht., 1 vocal score (67 p.); 34 cm. (Box 24, Folder 358)
      On cover: Pencil notes by Curjel.
      Stamped on title page: Universal Edition Wien.
      See also: Mahagonny [microform].
    - Mandelay-Song
    - Matrosen-Song
    - Mississippi legend
      See: Huckleberry Finn.
    - Much ado about love
      See: Firebrand of Florence.
    - [Na und (Sketches)], [1926 Mar.-1927 Apr.] [David Drew].; [36] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 10, Fr. 207-234. (Box 24, Folder 359)
      Libretto by Felix Joachimson.
      In pencil on p. with "Ouvertüre": Sketch for Zar...
      Also includes sketch for Herzog Theodor von Gothland [David Drew].
    - Ocean song
    - One touch of Venus, See also: B. Film Scores. One touch of Venus (Sketches).
    - [One touch of Venus] One touch of Venus, [1942-1943].; 1 score ([560] p. in various pagings); 34-38 cm. R. 10, Fr. 235-562. (Box 24; 25, Folder 360-361; 362)
      Holograph in ink and pencil, in part manuscript.
      Words by Ogden Nash not included.
      "Overture" is in copyist's hand.
      Vocal parts are not included.
      Contents: Act I: #1. Introduction (13 p.). No. 2. Opening (18 p.). #3. One touch of Venus (15 p.). No. 4. Venus awakening (4 p.). Venus' awakening (5 p.). No. 5. Curtain music (7 p.). No. 6. How much I love you (16 p.). No. 7. [same as No. 4]. No. 8. Mrs. Moats falls ([1] p.). No. 9. I'm a stranger here myself (16 p.). No. 10. Ballet (forty minutes for lunch) (37 p.). No. 11. Incidental music (3 p.). No. 12. Westwind (12 p.). No. 13. Way out west in Jersey (24 p.). No. 14. That's how I am sick of love (11 p.). No. 17. Foolish heart (15 p.). No. 18. Foolish heart dance (22 p.). No. 19. The trouble with women (19 p.). No. 20. Gloria disappears ([2] p.). No. 21. Speak low (18 p.). No. 22. Artist's ball (25 p.). No. 23. Dr. Crippen (22 p.). No. 24. Overture-Entr'acte (36 p.). No. 25. Very very very (18 p.). - Act II[?]: No. 26. 2nd Act-Reprise "Speak low" (8 p.). No. 27. Catch hatch (20 p.). No, 28. That's him (16 p.). Wooden wedding (14 p.). No. 30. Venus in Ozone Heights Ballet (31 p.). No. 31. Baccanale (26 p.). No. 33. Finaletto (5 p.) Who am I? (17 p.). Vive la difference ([14] p. - pencil sketch on back, incomplete?). Westwind dance (16 p.). Foolish heart waltz (pp. 13-16). (Opening) p. 7 original idea ([2] p.). [Opening] ([4] p.). Wooden wedding (incidental) ([6] p.). Exit wooden wedding (utility) (10 sheets - manuscript in another hand). Reprise westwind (Finale) ([8] p.).
    - [One touch of Venus] One touch of Venus, 16 parts; 27-36 cm. R. 10, Fr. 563-1038. R. 11, Fr. 1-852. (Box 25; 26; 27, Folder 363-368; 369-375; 376-383)
      Manuscript in copyists' hands in ink (in part, photocopies) with pencil additions.
      Includes parts for piano, clarinet I/alto saxophone, clarinet II/bass clarinet/alto saxophone, clarinet II/bass clarinet/alto saxophone, clarinet III/flute/alto saxophone, clarinet IV/piccolo/flute/tenor saxophone, trumpet I-II, trumpet III, trombone, violin A (stands 1-3), violin B (stands 1-2), viola, violoncello, double bass, percussion, guitar ("How much I love you" only), and conductor (for "Overture" and "How much I love you" only). Parts for National melodies, arranged by Chas. J. Roberts (9) and "National melodies" (Marseillaise, etc. - 6) laid in. Includes duplicates, and parts in different keys.
      Contents: Act I: #1. Introduction (13 p.). No. 2. Opening (18 p.). #3. One touch of Venus (15 p.). No. 4. Venus awakening (4 p.). Venus' awakening (5 p.). No. 5. Curtain music (7 p.). No. 6. How much I love you (16 p.). No. 7. [same as No. 4]. No. 8. Mrs. Moats falls ([1] p.). No. 9. I'm a stranger here myself (16 p.). No. 10. Ballet (forty minutes for lunch) (37 p.). No. 11. Incidental music (3 p.). No. 12. Westwind (12 p.). No. 13. Way out west in Jersey (24 p.). No. 14. That's how I am sick of love (11 p.). No. 17. Foolish heart (15 p.). No. 18. Foolish heart dance (22 p.). No. 19. The trouble with women (19 p.). No. 20. Gloria disappears ([2] p.). No. 21. Speak low (18 p.). No. 22. Artist's ball (25 p.). No. 23. Dr. Crippen (22 p.). No. 24. Overture-Entr'acte (36 p.). No. 25. Very very very (18 p.). - Act II[?]: No. 26. 2nd Act-Reprise "Speak low" (8 p.). No. 27. Catch hatch (20 p.). No, 28. That's him (16 p.). Wooden wedding (14 p.). No. 30. Venus in Ozone Heights Ballet (31 p.). No. 31. Baccanale (26 p.). No. 33. Finaletto (5 p.) Who am I? (17 p.). Vive la difference ([14] p. - pencil sketch on back, incomplete?). Westwind dance (16 p.). Foolish heart waltz (pp. 13-16). (Opening) p. 7 original idea ([2] p.). [Opening] ([4] p.). Wooden wedding (incidental) ([6] p.). Exit wooden.
    - [One touch of Venus. Barber shop. Text (Sketches)] Barber shop - Boles., [1] sheet; 13 x 21 cm. R. 11, Fr. 853. (Box 27, Folder 384)
      Manuscript in pencil in Nash's hand.
      "O. Nash" - on bottom of sheet.
    - [One touch of Venus. Earthbound. Text] Earthbound., [1] sheet; 27 cm. R. 11, Fr. 854. (Box 27, Folder 384)
    - [One touch of Venus. Fates. Text] Fates., [1] sheet; 26 cm. (Box 27, Folder 384)
    - [One touch of Venus. Flash rounds. Text] Flash rounds., [1] sheet; 31 cm. R. 11, Fr. 855. (Box 27, Folder 384)
    - [One touch of Venus. Foolish heart. Vocal score] Foolish heart / music by Kurt Weill; words by Ogden Nash. - New York: Chappell, c1943., 1 vocal score (5 p.); 31 cm. (Box 27, Folder 385)
      Pl. no.: C-1268-4.
    - [One touch of Venus. Fresh air and exercise. Text] Fresh air and exercise., [1] sheet; 32 cm. R. 11, Fr. 857. (Box 27, Folder 386)
    - [One touch of Venus. Fresh air and exercise. Text] Fresh air and exercise., [1] sheet; 27 cm. R. 11, Fr. 856. (Box 27, Folder 386)
    - [One touch of Venus. How much I love you. Text], 2 sheets; 32 cm. R. 11, Fr. 858-859. (Box 27, Folder 386)
    - [One touch of Venus. If I could find another rhyme for love. Text], [1] sheet; 26 cm. R. 11, Fr. 860. (Box 27, Folder 386)
      "0. Nash" - in ink on bottom of sheet.
    - [One touch of Venus. I'm a stranger here myself. Text], [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 28, Folder 387)
    - [One touch of Venus. I'm a stranger here myself. Text] I'm a stranger here myself: from "One touch of Venus" / lyrics by Ogden Nash., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 28, Folder 387)
    - [One touch of Venus. Jersey plunk. Text], [1] sheet; 32 cm. R. 12, Fr. 1. (Box 28, Folder 387)
    - [One touch of Venus. Libretto (Sketches)], [1] sheet; 27 cm. R. 12, Fr. 2. (Box 28, Folder 387)
      Manuscript in ink in Nash's hand.
      Begins: I am not like Circe...
    - [One touch of Venus. Love in a mist. Text] Love-in-a-mist., [1] sheet; 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 388)
    - [One touch of Venus. New art is true art. Text], 2 sheets; 32 cm. R. 12, Fr. 3-4. (Box 28, Folder 389)
      "O. Nash One Touch of Venus" - on bottom of each sheet.
    - [One touch of Venus. One touch of Venus. Text] One touch of Venus., [1] sheet; 28 cm. R. 12, Fr. 5. (Box 28, Folder 389)
    - [One touch of Venus. Same time, same place. Text] Same time, same place., [1] sheet; 27 cm. R. 12, Fr. 6. (Box 28, Folder 389)
    - [One touch of Venus. Same time, same place. Text] Same time, same place., [1] sheet; 27 cm. (Box 28, Folder 389)
      "0. Nash Venus" - on bottom of sheet.
    - [One touch of Venus. Selections. Vocal score], 1 vocal score ([118] p.); 34 cm. R. 12, Fr. 7-71. (Box 28, Folder 390)
      Holograph and manuscript in ink with pencil additions.
      Contents: Act I: Opening (11 p.). Who dealt (Four women) ([12] p.). Venus was a modest goddess (Trio) ([8] p.). How much I love you ([3] p.). Westwind (Boston) ([4] p.). I'm a stranger here myself (6 p. with pencil sketch at end). The Jersey Plunk (8, [2] p.). Dance ([6] p.). The trouble with women ([4] p.). Too soon ([4] p.). Dr. Crippen ([8] p.). It must be Ernie [Catch Hatch] (10 p.). That's him ([7] p.). Wooden wedding ([4] p.). Who am I? ([7] p.). Vive la différence ([4] p.). Doctor Crippen (10 p.).
    - One touch of Venus / Kurt Weill; Ogden Nash [c1943]., 1 score ([101] p.); 34 cm. R. 12, Fr. 72-123. (Box 28, Folder 391)
      Manuscript in copyist's hands (originals and photocopies).
      Contents [Numbers and titles assigned by Drew appear in brackets]: [2. New Art is True Art] Opening (12 sheets, original and 4 copies). [2. New Art is True Art] No. 2 (pp. 7-9). [3y. Venus Was a Modest Goddess]. The Modest Goddess (9 sheets, original and 3 copies), No. 3. One Touch of Venus (pp. 10-17). [3a] No. 4. Venus Awakening ([1] sheet). [4a] No. 7. Venus Entrance and [4b] No. 8. Mrs. Moats falls ([1] sheet). [5] 4. I'm a stranger here myself (6 p.). [photocopy negative with "No. 9" on first sheet laid in (sheets 23-28; 16 cm.)]. [6a] No. 11. Incidental after "Forty Minutes for Lunch" ([1] sheet). [6a] Incidental after "Forty Minutes for Lunch" (Ballet) ([1] sheet). [8y] The Jersey Plunk (8 sheets). [11y] Too soon ([4] p.). [11] Speak low (8 p.). [12] Doctor Crippen (10 p., words are typed on, "key of B minor" in pencil on first p.). [16] Catch Hatch! (16 p., 2 copies). [18] Wooden Wedding ([3] p.). [20b] No. 32. Finaletto (pp. 159-160). [20b] Finaletto ([2] p.).
    - [One touch of Venus (Sketches)], [108] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 12, Fr. 124-183. (Box 28, Folder 392)
    - [One touch of Venus (Sketches)], [104] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 12, Fr. 184-238. (Box 28, Folder 393)
    - [One touch of Venus (Sketches)], [4] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 12, Fr. 238-240. (Box 28, Folder 393)
      Drew notes that one p."...carries notes in another hand - presumably Agnes de Mille's."
    - [One touch of Venus (Sketches)], [5] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 12, Fr. 241-243. (Box 28, Folder 393)
    - [One touch of Venus (Sketches)] Orchestra changes Wednesday nite., [1] sheet; 28 cm. R. 12, Fr. 244. (Box 28, Folder 393)
    - [One touch of Venus. Something has happened. Text] Something has happened., [1] sheet; 32 cm. R. 12, Fr. 245. (Box 28, Folder 394)
    - [One touch of Venus. Speak low. Text] Speak low when you speak love., [1] sheet; 26 cm. R. 12, Fr. 246. (Box 28, Folder 394)
    - [One touch of Venus. Speak low. Text] Speak low when you speak love., [1] sheet; 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 394)
    - [One touch of Venus. Speak low. Text] Speak low: from "One touch of Venus" / lyrics by Ogden Nash., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 28, Folder 394)
    - [One touch of Venus. Speak low. Text] Speak low., [1] sheet [p. 6]; 28 cm. (Box 28, Folder 394)
    - [One touch of Venus. That's him. Text] That's him., [1] sheet; 32 cm. R. 12, Fr. 247. (Box 28, Folder 394)
    - [One touch of Venus. That's him. Text] That's him., [1] sheet; 26 cm. R. 12, Fr. 248. (Box 28, Folder 394)
      "O. Nash Venus" - on bottom of sheet.
    - [One touch of Venus. That's him. Text] That's him., [1] sheet; 32 cm. R. 12, Fr. 250. (Box 28, Folder 394)
    - [One touch of Venus. That's him. Text] That's him., [1] sheet; 26 cm. R. 12, Fr. 249. (Box 28, Folder 394)